In the previous video, I mentioned that broadcasting
在之前的视频中 我提到了广播(broadcasting)
is another technique that you can use
to make your Python code run faster.
这是另外一种使你的python代码运行得更快的技术
In this video, let's delve into how
broadcasting in Python actually works.
现在我们将深入了解它的broadcasting具体是如何工作的
Let's suppose today broadcasting with an example.
让我们用一个例子引出今天要讲的broadcasting
In this matrix, I've shown the number
of calories from carbohydrates,
这个矩阵中展示了4种不同食物 以及每100g食物中的
proteins, and fats in 100 grams of four different foods.
碳水化合物 蛋白质和脂肪中含有的卡路里
So for example, a 100 grams of apples turns out,
例如 每100g苹果
has 56 calories from carbs, and
much less from proteins and fats.
有56卡路里来自碳水化合物
蛋白质和脂肪中仅含有很少卡路里
Whereas, in contrast, a 100 grams of
beef has 104 calories from protein and
相反，100g牛肉的蛋白质中含有104卡路里
135 calories from fat.
脂肪中含有135卡路里
Now, let's say your goal is to
calculate the percentage of calories
你的任务是分别计算这四种食物的
from carbs, proteins and fats for each of the four foods.
碳水化合物、蛋白质和脂肪产生的卡路里的百分比
So, for example, if you look at this column and
我们以这一列为例
add up the numbers in that column
you get that 100 grams of apple
把该列所有数字加起来 你会发现每100g苹果
has 56 plus 1.2 plus 1.8 so that's 59 calories.
56+1.2+1.8 有59卡路里
And so as a percentage the percentage of
下来算百分比
calories from carbohydrates in an apple would
苹果的碳水化合物所产生的卡路里
be 56 over 59, that's about 94.9%.
占56/59 大约是94.9%
So most of the calories in an apple
come from carbs, whereas in contrast,
因此苹果的卡路里主要来自碳水化合物
most of the calories of beef come
from protein and fat and so on.
相反 牛肉的卡路里主要来自蛋白质和脂肪
So the calculation you want is really
to sum up each of the four columns
你需要做的运算就是把这个矩阵的4列数字分别加起来
of this matrix to get the total number
of calories in 100 grams of apples,
得到100g苹果
beef, eggs, and potatoes.
牛肉、鸡蛋、土豆总共含有的卡路里
And then to divide throughout the matrix,
然后对整个矩阵做除法运算
so as to get the percentage of
calories from carbs, proteins and
得到四种食物的碳水化合物 蛋白质 脂肪
fats for each of the four foods.
分别产生卡路里的百分比
So the question is, can you do
this without an explicit for-loop?
问题是 你可以不用for循环完成么
Let's take a look at
how you could do that.
我们看一下你可以怎么实现
What I'm going to do is
show you how you can set,
我接下来向你展示如何解决该问题
say this matrix equal to
three by four matrix A.
让这个矩阵等于一个3*4的矩阵A
And then with one line of Python code
we're going to sum down the columns.
接下来我们用一行Python代码把矩阵按列加起来
So we're going to get four numbers
corresponding to the total number
我们将得到4个数字 表示这四种食物
of calories in these four
different types of foods,
所含卡路里总数
100 grams of these four
different types of foods.
100g 四种不同的食物
And I'm going to use a second line
of Python code to divide each of
我接下来会用第二行Python代码将四列分别除以
the four columns by
their corresponding sum.
他们对应的总和
If that verbal description
wasn't very clearly,
如果口头表述还不够清楚的话
hopefully it will be clearer in a second
when we look in the Python code.
希望我们可以通过Python代码表述清楚
So here we are in the Jupyter notebook.
我们打开Jupyter notebook
I've already written this first
piece of code to prepopulate
我已经写好了第一段代码
the matrix A with the numbers we had
just now, so we'll hit shift enter and
将我们之前给出的数值存入矩阵A 我们按下shift enter
just run that, so there's the matrix A.
运行代码 就有了矩阵A
And now here are the two
lines of Python code.
接下来是两行Python代码
First, we're going to compute
cal = A.sum(axis=0).
首先 我们计算cal = A.sum(axis=0)
And axis equals 0 means to sum vertically.
axis=0表示纵向求和
We'll say more about that in a little bit.
我们稍后会更细致的讨论
And then print cal.
然后打印cal
So we've sum vertically.
我们已经纵向的把他们加起来了
Now 59 is the total number of
calories in the apple, 239 was
59是苹果总共含有的卡路里
the total number of calories in the beef
and the eggs and potato and so on.
239是牛肉总共含有的卡路里 后面是鸡蛋 土豆
And then with a compute
接下来计算
percentage = A/cal.reshape(1,4).
Actually we want percentages,
so multiply by 100 here.
我们想要的是百分比，因此这里乘100
And then let's print percentage.
然后我们打印percentage
Let's run that.
运行
And so that command we've taken the matrix A and
我们用这条指令把矩阵A除以
divided it by this one by four matrix.
这个1*4的矩阵
And this gives us
the matrix of percentages.
我们得到了这个百分比矩阵
So as we worked out kind of by
hand just now in the apple there
就像我之前手算的苹果那样
was a first column 94.9% of
the calories are from carbs.
94.9%的卡路里都来自碳水化合物
Let's go back to the slides.
我们回到幻灯片
So just to repeat the two
lines of code we had,
重复一下我们写的两行代码
this is what have written
out in the Jupyter notebook.
这是我们在Jupyter notebook中写的
To add a bit of detail this parameter,
讨论一下关于这个参数的一些细节
(axis = 0), means that you
want Python to sum vertically.
(axis=0)表示你希望Python纵向求和
So if this is axis 0 this
means to sum vertically,
axis 0意味着纵向相加
whereas the horizontal axis is axis 1.
相反 横向是axis 1
So be able to write axis 1 or sum
horizontally instead of sum vertically.
所以 可以写axis 1横向求和
And then this command here,
这是代码
this is an example of Python
broadcasting where you take a matrix A.
这是一个Python broadcasting的例子 你有一个矩阵A
So this is a three by four matrix and
you divide it by a one by four matrix.
矩阵A是一个3*4的矩阵 你用它除以一个1*4的矩阵
And technically, after this first
line of codes cal, the variable cal,
严格来说 在第一行代码之后 变量cal
is already a one by four matrix.
已经是一个1*4的矩阵了
So technically you don't need
to call reshape here again, so
所以严格来说 你不需要在这里再次调用reshape
that's actually a little bit redundant.
这事实上有一点冗余
But when I'm writing Python codes if
I'm not entirely sure what matrix,
但是如果我在写Python代码的时候并不完全确定矩阵的维度
what what the dimensions of a matrix I often
would just call a reshape command just to
我通常会调用reshape指令
make sure that it's the right
column vector or the row vector or
确保这是一个合适的列向量或者行向量
whatever you want it to be.
或者你想要的维度
The reshape command is a constant time.
reshape指令仅需常量时间
It's a order one operation
that's very cheap to call.
调用他并不会开销并不大
So don't be shy about using the reshape
command to make sure that your matrices
所以调用reshape不用为难 确保你的矩阵
are the size you need it to be.
是你需要的尺寸
Now, let's explain in greater detail how
this type of operation works, right?
下来 我们解释这一操作更多的细节
We had a three by four matrix and
we divided it by a one by four matrix.
我们有一个3*4的矩阵 我们用它除以1*4的矩阵
So, how can you divide a three by
four matrix by a one by four matrix?
我们如何让一个3*4的矩阵除以1*4的矩阵呢？
Or by one by four vector?
或者说1*4的向量
Let's go through a few more
examples of broadcasting.
让我们继续看几个broadcasting的例子
If you take a 4 by 1 vector and
add it to a number, what
如果你有一个4*1的向量 给他加一个数
Python will do is take this number and auto-expand
Python会自动的将这个数
it into a four by one vector as well, as follows.
扩展成为一个4*1的向量 例如
And so the vector [1, 2, 3, 4]
向量[1, 2, 3, 4]
plus the number 100 ends up
with that vector on the right.
加上数字100 得到右边那个向量
You're adding a 100 to every element,
and in fact we use this form of
你给每个数字都加了100 事实上我们在之前的视频中
broadcasting where that constant was
the parameter b in an earlier video.
使用了这种形式的broadcasting 那个视频的常数是b
And this type of broadcasting works with
both column vectors and row vectors,
这种类型的broadcasting同样适用与行向量和列向量
and in fact we use a similar form of
broadcasting earlier with the constant
事实上 在之前logistic回归的视频中我们使用了类似形式的
we've added to a vector being
the parameter b in logistic regression.
broadcasting 我们在加法中使用了向量化的参数b
Here's another example.
下面是另一个例子
Let's say you have a two
by three matrix and
假设你有一个2*3的矩阵
you add it to this one by n matrix.
你给它加上这个1*n的矩阵
So the general case would be if you
更一般的情况是 如果你有一个
have some (m,n) matrix here and
(m*n)的矩阵
you add it to a (1,n) matrix.
你给它加上(1*n)的矩阵
What Python will do is copy the matrix m,
Python将会拷贝这个矩阵m次
times to turn this into m by n matrix, so instead of this one by
将这个矩阵变为m*n的矩阵 来看这个1*3的矩阵
three matrix it'll copy it twice in
this example to turn it into this.
在这个例子中 他会被拷贝两次 变成这个样子
Also, two by three matrix and
we'll add these so
这是2*3的矩阵 我们把他们加起来
you'll end up with the sum on the right, okay?
你将会得到右边的结果
So you taken, you added 100 to the first column,
你给第一列加100
added 200 to second column, added 300 to the third column.
第二列加200 第三列加300
And this is basically what we did on the previous slide,
这基本上就是我们在上一张幻灯片做的操作
except that we use a division operation
instead of an addition operation.
只是我们使用了除法而不是加法
So one last example,
whether you have a (m,n) matrix and
最后一个例子 如果你有一个(m*n)的矩阵
you add this to a (m,1) vector,
(m,1) matrix.
和这个(m*1)的向量相加
Then just copy this n times horizontally.
就将这个横向拷贝n次
So you end up with an (m,n) matrix.
你最后得到一个(m*n)的矩阵
So as you can imagine you copy
it horizontally three times.
你可以想象你横向拷贝了他三次
And you add those.
然后把这两个矩阵加起来
So when you add them you end up with this.
你把他们加起来 会得到这个
So we've added 100 to the first row and
added 200 to the second row.
我们给第一行加了100 第二行加了200
Here's the more general principle
of broadcasting in Python.
关于Python中broadcasting更一般的原理
If you have an (m,n) matrix and you add or
如果你有一个(m*n)的矩阵 你把他和
subtract or multiply or
divide with a (1,n) matrix,
一个(1*n)的矩阵做四则运算
then this will copy it m
times into an (m,n) matrix.
就会把这个(1*n)的矩阵拷贝m次成为一个(m*n)的矩阵
And then apply the addition,
subtraction, and
然后再在元素层面应用加法 减法
multiplication of division elementwise.
乘法 除法等等
If conversely, you were to take the (m,n)
matrix and add, subtract, multiply,
相反 你有一个(m*n)的矩阵和一个(m*1)的矩阵
divide by an (m,1) matrix,
then also this would copy it now n times.
做四则运算 (m*1)的矩阵会被拷贝n次
And turn that into an (m,n) matrix and
then apply the operation elementwise.
变成一个(m*n)的矩阵再在元素层级做运算
Just one of the broadcasting,
which is if you have an (m,1) matrix,
如果你有一个(m*1)的矩阵
so that's really a column vector
like [1,2,3], and you add,
比如一个具体的列向量[1,2,3] 你把他和一个
subtract, multiply or
divide by a real number.
实数做四则运算
So maybe a (1,1) matrix.
也可能是(1*1)的矩阵
So such as that plus 100,
then you end up copying
例如 加上100 然后你拷贝
this real number n times until you'll
also get another (n,1) matrix.
这个实数n次得到一个(n*1)的矩阵
And then you perform the operation such
as addition on this example element-wise.
然后你在元素层级做运算 例如加法
And something similar also works for row vectors.
类似的 行向量也是以类似的方式运行
The fully general version of broadcasting
can do even a little bit more than this.
完整的broadcasting还有更多形式
If you're interested you can read the documentation for
如过你对此感到很有兴趣 你可以在
NumPy, and look at broadcasting in that documentation.
NumPy的文档中继续研究broadcasting
That gives an even slightly more general definition of broadcasting.
文档给了broadcasting更通用的定义
But the ones on the slide are the main
forms of broadcasting that you end up
但是讲义上的是你在实现
needing to use when you
implement a neural network.
神经网络的过程中需要的形式
Before we wrap up,
just one last comment, which is for
我们结束之前 最后一点说明
those of you that are used to
programming in either MATLAB or
如果你使用过MATLAB或
Octave, if you've ever used the MATLAB or
Octave function bsxfun
Octave 如果你使用过他们的一个函数bsxfun
in neural network programming bsxfun does
something similar, not quite the same.
在神经网络编程中 bsxfun的效果与这个很相似但不完全相同
But it is often used for similar purpose
as what we use broadcasting in Python for.
但它和我们在python中使用广播的目的是类似的
But this is really only for very advanced MATLAB and
这真的是只针对高级的MATLAB和
Octave users, if you've not heard of this,
don't worry about it.
Octave用户 如果你没有听说过 不用担心
You don't need to know it when you're
coding up neural networks in Python.
你在使用Python写神经网络的过程中并不需要知道它
So, that was broadcasting in Python.
这就是Python的broadcasting
I hope that when you do the programming
homework that broadcasting will allow you
希望你做编程作业的时候broadcasting能够
to not only make a code run faster,
使你的代码运行的更快
but also help you get what you want
done with fewer lines of code.
让你用更少的代码完成你想做的
Before you dive into the programming
excercise, I want to share with you just
在你去做编程作业之前 我想和你分享
one more set of ideas,
which is that there's some tips and
一些技巧 这些技巧
tricks that I've found reduces
the number of bugs in my Python code and
可以减少我的Python代码中的bug
that I hope will help you too.
我希望同样对你有用
So with that,
let's talk about that in the next video.
这些技巧我们在下一个视频中讨论